Walk around for four months with three wishes,
تجولت لمدة 4 اشهر و تمنيت 3 امنيات
and all the ideas will start to percolate up.
وستتجمع كل الافكار
I think everybody should do it -- think that you've got three wishes.
اعتقد أن على الجميع ان يقوم بذلك - أن تعتقد ان لديك 3 امنيات
And what would you do? It's actually a great exercise
وما الذي ستعمله؟ في الحقيقة ذلك تمرين رائع
to really drill down to the things that you feel are important,
ان تنقب عن الاشياء التي تشعر انها هامة،
and really reflect on the world around us.
و تفكر في العالم من حولك
And thinking that, can an individual actually do something,
و ان تعتقد انه بمجرد ان يقوم أي فرد بعمل شيء فعليا،
or come up with something,
او ان يأتي بشيء جديد،
that may actually get some traction out there and make a difference?
قد يحدث ذلك بعض التغيير الفعلي؟
Inspired by nature -- that's the theme here.
ان تلهمك الطبيعة - فتلك هي الفكرة هنا.
And I think, quite frankly, that's where I started.
و اعتقد صراحةً انني أنطلقت من هناك
I became very interested in the landscape as a Canadian.
كوني كندياً اصبحت مهتماً جداً بالمناظر الطبيعية
We have this Great North. And there was a pretty small population,
لدينا منطقة الشمال الرائعة و فيها عدد قليل من السكان،
and my father was an avid outdoorsman.
وكان والدي رجل يحب الهواء الطلق.
So I really had a chance to experience that.
ولذلك حظيت بفرصة عيش تلك التجربة
And I could never really understand exactly what it was, or how it was informing me.
ولم يكن بإمكاني ان افهم بالضبط ماهيتها او كيفية تعلمي منها
But what I think it was telling me
ولكن ما اعتقد انها كانت تخبرني به
is that we are this transient thing that's happening,
هو أننا هذا الشيء العابر الذي يحدث.
and that the nature that you see out there -- the untouched shorelines,
وأن الطبيعة التي تراها - مثل الشواطئ البكر،
the untouched forest that I was able to see --
والغابة البكر التي تمكنت من رؤيتها -
really bring in a sense of that geological time,
تجعلنا نتحسس ذلك الزمن الجيولوجي ،
that this has gone on for a long time,
و أن ذلك يحدث منذ زمن بعيد،
and we're experiencing it in a different way.
ونعيشها بطريقة مختلفة.
And that, to me, was a reference point that I think I needed to have
وبالنسية لي كانت تلك نقطة مرجعية اعتقدت انني كنت بحاجتها
to be able to make the work that I did.
كي اتمكن من عمل ما عملت.
And I did go out, and I did this picture of grasses coming through in the spring,
وقد خرجت والتقطت هذه الصورة للاعشاب التي تنمو في فصل الربيع
along a roadside.
على جانبي الطريق.
This rebirth of grass. And then I went out for years
هذا الانبات الجديد للعشب. وبعدها خرجت لسنين
trying to photograph the pristine landscape.
محاولاً ان اصور هذه المناظر البكر.
But as a fine-art photographer I somehow felt
ولكن كوني مصور فنون جميلة شعرت
that it wouldn't catch on out there,
انني لن اتمكن من التقاط تلك اللحظة
that there would be a problem with trying to make this as a fine-art career.
انه يمكن ان يكون هناك مشكلة في محاولة جعل هذه مهنة في الفنون الجميلة
And I kept being sucked into this genre of the calendar picture,
وبقيت متعلقاً بهذا النوع من صور التقويم،
or something of that nature, and I couldn't get away from it.
او شيء ما من تلك الطبيعة، ولم اتمكن من الابتعاد عن ذلك.
So I started to think of, how can I rethink the landscape?
ولذلك بدأت أفكر ، كيف اعيد النظر في المناظر الطبيعية؟
I decided to rethink the landscape
فقررت ان اعيد النظر في تلك المناظر
as the landscape that we've transformed.
على أنها المناظر التي قمنا بتحويلها.
I had a bit of an epiphany being lost in Pennsylvania,
كنت منزعجاُ بعض الشيء كوني ضللت الطريق في بنسلفينيا.
and I took a left turn trying to get back to the highway.
وقمت بالاستدارة ناحية اليسار محاولاً العودة إلى الطريق السريع
And I ended up in a town called Frackville.
ولكني وصلت في النهاية لبلدة تسمى فراكفيل.
I got out of the car, and I stood up,
فترجلت من السيارة ، ووقفت هنالك ،
and it was a coal-mining town. I did a 360 turnaround,
كانت بلدة فيها منجم لاستخراج الفحم
and that became one of the most surreal landscapes I've ever seen.
و أصبح ذلك أحد أكثر المناظر الخيالية التي رأيتها في حياتي
Totally transformed by man.
تم تحويلها بالكامل من قبل الإنسان.
And that got me to go out and look at mines like this,
و دفعني ذلك إلى الخروج و البحث عن مناجم كهذه
and go out and look at the largest industrial incursions
و النظر إلى أكبر الغزوات الصناعية
in the landscape that I could find.
في المشهد الذي استطعت ان اجده.
And that became the baseline of what I was doing.
واصبح ذلك نقطة انطلاق لما أقوم به.
And it also became the theme that I felt that I could hold onto,
واصبح ايضا الفكرة التي شعرت انني استطع ان اتمسك بها،
and not have to re-invent myself --
ولا أحتاج أن اعيد صياغة نفسي
that this theme was large enough to become a life's work,
وكانت هذه الفكرة كبيرة كفاية كي تصبح عملي في الحياة
to become something that I could sink my teeth into
أن تصبح شيئاً أستطيع أن أغرز أسناني فيه
and just research and find out where these industries are.
والقيام بالبحث لاكتشاف مكان هذه الصناعات
And I think one of the things I also wanted to say in my thanks,
واعتقد ان احد الاشياء التي اردت ايضاً ان اقولها في شكري
which I kind of missed,
والتي لم اذكرها سهواً،
was to thank all the corporations who helped me get in.
هي ان اشكر كل الشركات التي ساعدتني في الوصول لمرادي.
Because it took negotiation for almost every one of these photographs --
لأن الأمر تطلب مني اجراء مفاوضات لكل صورة من هذه الصور --
to get into that place to make those photographs,
والوصول الى ذلك المكان و اخذ هذه الصور
and if it wasn't for those people letting me in
ولو لم يسمح لي اولئك الاشخاص بالدخول
at the heads of those corporations,
على المسؤولين عن هذه الشركات،
I would have never made this body of work.
لما تمكنت من القيام بهذا العمل.
So in that respect, to me, I'm not against the corporation.
ولذا بذلك الخصوص، وبالنسبة لي، انا لست ضد الشركات
I own a corporation. I work with them,
فانا عندي شركة و اعمل بها
and I feel that we all need them and they're important.
واشعر اننا بحاجة للشركات فهي مهمة.
But I am also for sustainability.
ولكني ايضاً ادعم الاستدامة.
So there's this thing that is pulling me in both directions.
وبالتالي هناك شيء يجذبني في كلا الاتجاهين.
And I'm not making an indictment towards what's happening here,
و أنا لا أحاول توجيه الاتهام لما يحدث هنا،
but it is a slow progression.
ولكنه تقدم بطيء
So I started thinking, well, we live in all these ages of man:
لذا بدأت بالتفكير: حسناً، نعيش في عصور الانسان هذه:
the Stone Age, and the Iron Age, and the Copper Age.
العصر الحجري و العصر الحديدي و العصر النحاسي
And these ages of man are still at work today.
وعصور الانسان هذه مازالت تعمل للآن،
But we've become totally disconnected from them.
ولكننا اصبحنا منفصلين عنها بالكامل.
There's something that we're not seeing there.
هناك أمر لا نستطيع رؤيته هناك.
And it's a scary thing as well. Because when we start looking
وهو شيء مخيف ايضا. لاننا عندما نبدأ بالنظر
at the collective appetite for our lifestyles,
إلى الشهية التجميعية في كل انماط حياتنا
and what we're doing to that landscape --
وإلى ما نقوم به تجاه تلك المناظر الطبيعية
that, to me, is something that is a very sobering moment for me to contemplate.
وذلك بالنسبة لي لحظة واقعية للتأمل.
And through my photographs,
ومن خلال صوري،
I'm hoping to be able to engage the audiences of my work,
آمل ان اتمكن من ان أُشرك من يرى صوري
and to come up to it and not immediately be rejected by the image.
وان يطلع عليها ولا يرفضها
Not to say, "Oh my God, what is it?" but to be challenged by it --
وليس ان تقولوا: يا إلهي! ما هذا! ولكن يجب ان تتحدوا ذلك
to say, "Wow, this is beautiful," on one level,
وان تقول: واو ما اروع ذلك من ناحية
but on the other level, "This is scary. I shouldn't be enjoying it."
ولكن من الناحية الاخرى، هذا مروع. علي الا استمتع به.
Like a forbidden pleasure. And it's that forbidden pleasure
كالمتعة المحرمة. وتلك المتعة محرمة
that I think is what resonates out there,
أعتقد أن ذلك هو صدى ما هو هنالك
and it gets people to look at these things,
وتجعل الاشخاص ينظرون إلى هذه الاشياء
and it gets people to enter it. And it also, in a way, defines kind of what I feel, too --
ويدخلونها. و ايضا بطريقة ما تحدد ما اشعر به ايضا
that I'm drawn to have a good life.
انه انا صممت كي احيا حياة طيبة
I want a house, and I want a car.
اريد بيتا و سيارة
But there's this consequence out there.
ولكن لذلك ثمن
And how do I begin to have that attraction, repulsion?
كيف بدأت أشعر بذلك الانجذاب و الرفض؟
It's even in my own conscience I'm having it,
وحتى في ضميري
and here in my work, I'm trying to build that same toggle.
وهنا في عملي،
These things that I photographed -- this tire pile here
وهذه الاشياء التي صورت كصورة كومة الإطارات هنا
had 45 million tires in it. It was the largest one.
فيها 45 مليون إطار. كانت اكبر كومة
It was only about an hour-and-a-half away from me, and it caught fire
كانت على بعد ساعة و نصف مني و اشتعلت بالنيران
about four years ago. It's around Westley, California, around Modesto.
قبل اربع سنوات. حول ويستلي، كاليفورنيا و بالقرب من موديستو
And I decided to start looking at something that, to me, had --
وقررت ان ابدا النظر الى شيئ بالنسبة لي --
if the earlier work of looking at the landscape
لو كانت اول اعمالي في التمعن في المناظر
had a sense of lament to what we were doing to nature,
كان بها معنى للاسى على ما نقوم به تجاه الطبيعة
in the recycling work that you're seeing here
في اعمال اعادة التدوير التي ترونها هنا
was starting to point to a direction. To me, it was our redemption.
كانت نقطة البداية في اتجاه ما. وبالنسبة لي كانت بمثابة منقذنا
That in the recycling work that I was doing,
انه في عمل التدوير الذي كنت اقوم به
I'm looking for a practice, a human activity that is sustainable.
كنت ابحث عن ممارسة- لنشاط انساني فيه استدامة
That if we keep putting things, through industrial and urban existence,
اننا لو استمرينا في إعادة الاشياء الموجودة في الاماكن المدنية و الصناعية
back into the system --
في الاستعمال من جديد
if we keep doing that -- we can continue on.
اذا استمررنا بعمل ذلك فبإمكاننا المضي قدماً
Of course, listening at the conference,
بالطبع عند الاستماع للكلمات في المؤتمر
there's many, many things that are coming. Bio-mimicry,
هناك العديد والعديد من الاشياء على الطريق. كتقليد الطبيعة
and there's many other things that are coming on stream --
وهناك العديد من الاشياء التي سيبدأ تشغيلها مثل
nanotechnology that may also prevent us from having
تكنولوجيا النانو التي قد تمنعنا من
to go into that landscape and tear it apart.
الذهاب الى الطبيعة و تدميرها
And we all look forward to those things.
وجميعا نتطلع لمثل هذه الامور
But in the meantime, these things are scaling up.
و لكن في الوقت الراهن ، فإن هذه الأشياء تنمو
These things are continuing to happen.
وتستمر هذه الامور بالحدوث
What you're looking at here -- I went to Bangladesh,
ما تروه الآن-- ذهبت لبنغلادش
so I started to move away from North America;
لذا بدأت بالابتعاد عن امريكا الشمالية
I started to look at our world globally.
وبدأت النظر الى عالمنا بشكل عالمي
These images of Bangladesh
وهذا ما حصلت عليه-- هذه الصور من بنغلادش
came out of a radio program I was listening to.
اتت من برنامج إذاعي كنت استمع اليه
They were talking about Exxon Valdez,
وكانت تتحدث عن إكسون فالدز
and that there was going to be a glut of oil tankers
أنه سيكون هنالك تخمة من صهاريج النفط
because of the insurance industries.
بسبب شركات التامين
And that those oil tankers needed to be decommissioned,
وينبغي على هذه الصهاريج الخروج من الخدمة
and 2004 was going to be the pinnacle.
و أن ٢٠٠٤ سيكون القمة
And I thought, "My God, wouldn't that be something?"
وقلت في نفسي "يا إلهي! سيكون ذلك شيئا مذهلاً؟"
To see the largest vessels of man being deconstructed by hand,
ان ترى اكبر الأوعية من صنع الانسان تفكك يدوياً
literally, in third-world countries.
حرفياً ، في بلدان العالم الثالث.
So originally I was going to go to India.
لذا بالاصل كنت انوي الذهاب للهند
And I was shut out of India because of a Greenpeace situation there,
و منعت من الدخول للهند بسبب وضع ما هنالك
and then I was able to get into Bangladesh,
وبعدها تمكنت من الوصول لبنغلادش
and saw for the first time a third world, a view of it,
ورأيت للمرة الاولى العالم الثالث، مشهد منه
that I had never actually thought was possible.
لم اتوقع في حياتي ان يكون ممكناً
130 million people living in an area the size of Wisconsin --
ان يعيش 130 مليون نسمة في منطقة بحجم ويسكونزين
people everywhere -- the pollution was intense,
الناس في كل مكان و التلوث كثيف
and the working conditions were horrible.
وظروف العمل قاسية
Here you're looking at some oil fields in California,
هنا تنظرالى بعض حقول النفط في كاليفورنيا
some of the biggest oil fields. And again, I started to think that --
احد اكبر الحقول النفطية. و كذلك بدأت بالتفكير--
there was another epiphany --
كان هنالك لحظة تأمل أخرى
that the whole world I was living in was
ان العالم كله الذي اعيش فيه كان يخلق
a result of having plentiful oil.
نتيجة لوفرة النفط
And that, to me, was again something that I started building on,
ذلك بالنسبة لي كان شيء بدأت أبني عليه
and I continued to build on.
وواصلت البناء عليه
So this is a series I'm hoping to have ready
لذلك هذه سلسلة آمل ان تكون جاهزة
in about two or three years,
في غضون سنتين او ثلاث
under the heading of "The Oil Party."
تحت عنوان حزب النفط
Because I think everything that we're involved in --
لاني اعتقد ان كل شيء نشترك فيه
our clothing, our cars, our roads, and everything -- are directly a result.
من ملابسنا و سياراتنا وطرقنا وكل شيئ هو نتيجة مباشرة.
I'm going to move to some pictures of China.
سانتقل لبعض الصور من الصين
And for me China -- I started photographing it four years ago,
وعبر الصين-- بدأت تصويرها قبل اربع سنوات
and China truly is a question of sustainability in my mind,
وبحق إن الصين مسألة استدامة في ذهني
not to mention that China, as well,
ولا داعي لذكر ان الصين ايضاً
has a great effect on the industries that I grew up around.
لديها تاثير كبير على صناعات ترعرعت وهي حولي
I came out of a blue-collar town,
لان بلدتي هي بلدة صناعية
a GM town, and my father worked at GM,
بلدة جينرال موتورز، و قد عمل والدي فيها
so I was very familiar with that kind of industry
لذا كنت مدركاً جيداً لنوع الصناعة تلك
and that also informed my work. But you know,
وذلك عبر عن عملي. ولكن كما تعلمون
to see China and the scale at which it's evolving, is quite something.
ان تروا الصين و المدى الذي تتطور فيه، انه شيء عجيب
So what you see here is the Three Gorges Dam,
ما ترونه هنا هو سد الممرات الثلاث
and this is the largest dam by 50 percent ever attempted by man.
وهو اعظم سد بناه الانسان على الاطلاق
Most of the engineers around the world left the project
وقد غادر معظم المهندسون المشروع
because they said, "It's just too big."
لانهم قالوا ان السد اكبر مما ينبغي
In fact, when it did actually fill with water a year and a half ago,
في الحقيقة عندما امتلئ بالماء قبل سنة و نصف
they were able to measure a wobble within the earth as it was spinning.
تمكن العلماء من قياس تذبذب ضمن الأرض خلال دورانها.
It took fifteen days to fill it.
استغرق ملؤه خمسة عشر يوما
So this created a reservoir 600 kilometers long,
مما ادى الى وجود خزان مائي بطول 600 كم
one of the largest reservoirs ever created.
وهو اكبر خزان صناعي تم إنشاؤه على الإطلاق.
And what was also one of the bigger projects around that
واحد اكبر المشاريع المرافقة للسد كان
was moving 13 full-size cities up out of the reservoir,
نقل 13 مدينة مأهولة بالكامل من الخزان
and flattening all the buildings so they could make way for the ships.
وإزالة كل الابنية ليفسحوا المجال للسفن
This is a "before and after." So that was before.
هذه مقارنة. هذا من قبل
And this is like 10 weeks later, demolished by hand.
وهنا بعد 10 اسابيع، أزيل يدوياً
I think 11 of the buildings they used dynamite,
واعتقد انهم استخدموا الديناميت في إزالة 11 بناءً
everything else was by hand. That was 10 weeks later.
اما ما تبقى فازيل يدوياً. وهنا بعد 10 اسابيع
And this gives you an idea.
وهذا يعطيكم فكرة
And it was all the people who lived in those homes,
من جديد عن-- كل الناس الذين عاشوا في هذه المنازل
were the ones that were actually taking it apart
كانوا نفسهم من عملوا على إزالتها
and working, and getting paid per brick to take their cities apart.
وعملوا وتقاضوا اجرا لازالة كل طوبة من المدينة
And these are some of the images from that.
وهذه بعض الصور لذلك
So I spent about three trips to the Three Gorges Dam,
وقد ذهبت ثلاث مرات إلى سد الممرات الثلاث
looking at that massive transformation of a landscape.
وشاهدت التحول الهائل للمنظر
And it looks like a bombed-out landscape, but it isn't.
ويبدو كمنظر تفجير, اليس كذلك؟و لكنه ليس كذلك.
What it is, it's a landscape that is an intentional one.
ما ذلك؟ انه منظر مقصود.
This is a need for power, and they're willing to go through this
هذه الحاجة للطاقة، ويرغبون بالاستمرار بذلك
massive transformation, on this scale, to get that power.
تحولات هائلة على هذا القدر للحصول على تلك الطاقة
And again, it's actually a relief for what's going on in China
ومن جديد هذا نوع مريح عن الاشياء التي تجري في الصين
because I think on the table right now,
لاني اعتقد ان يوجد على الطاولة الان
there's 27 nuclear power stations to be built.
مشاريع بناء 27 محطة نووية
There hasn't been one built in North America for 20 years
لم يبنى اي محطة في امريكا الشمالية خلال العشرين سنة الماضية
because of the "NIMBY" problem -- "Not In My BackYard."
وذلك بسبب اعتراض الناس على إنشائها بالقرب من مكان إقامتهم.
But in China they're saying, "No, we're putting in 27 in the next 10 years."
ولكن في الصين يقولون لا ، "سنبني 27 محطة في السنوات العشر القادمة"
And coal-burning furnaces are going in there
وبالاضافة للأفران التي تحرق الفحم هناك
for hydroelectric power literally weekly.
بغية الحصول على الطافة الهيدروليكية وبشكل اسبوعي
So coal itself is probably one of the largest problems.
لذا فان الفحم بذاته احد اعظم المشاكل
And one of the other things that happened in the Three Gorges --
واحد الاشياء الاخرى التي حدثت في الممرات الثلاث--
a lot of the agricultural land that you see there on the left was also lost;
فقدان الكثير من الاراضي الزراعية التي ترونها على ناحية اليسار
some of the most fertile agricultural land was lost in that.
خسرنا احد اخصب الاراضي الزراعية بسبب ذلك
And 1.2 to 2 million people were relocated,
وبالاضافة الى تهجير اكثر من 2 مليون شخص
depending on whose statistics you're looking at.
و ذلك تابع لمصدر الاحصائيات التي تراها
And this is what they were building.
وهذا ما كانوا يقومون ببناءه
This is Wushan, one of the largest cities that was relocated.
هذه ووشان احد اكبر المدن التي تم نقلها.
This is the town hall for the city.
وهنا القيادة المركزية او مجلس المدينة
And again, the rebuilding of the city -- to me, it was sad to see
ايضا كانت عملية اعادة بناء المدينة عملية محزنة ان اراها
that they didn't really grab a lot of, I guess,
اي انهم لم يتعلموا بشكل كاف على ما اعتقد
what we know here, in terms of urban planning.
ما نعرفه هنا فيما يتعلق بتخطيط المدن
There were no parks; there were no green spaces.
فلم يكن هناك حدائق او اي مساحات خضراء
Very high-density living on the side of a hill.
فكثافة عالية من السكان تقطن جانب التلة
And here they had a chance to rebuild cities from the bottom up,
وهنا لديهم فرصة في بناء المدن من الاسفل للاعلى
but somehow were not connecting with them.
لكننا بطريقة ما لا نتصل معهم
Here is a sign that, translated, says, "Obey the birth control law.
وهنا اشارة تقول " التزموا بقانون تنظيم الاسرة".
Build our science, civilized and advanced idea of marriage and giving birth."
ابنوا علومنا. فكرة متحضرة ومتقدمة عن الزواج و إنجاب الأطفال.
So here, if you look at this poster,
لذا عندما تنظرون الى هذا الاعلان
it has all the trappings of Western culture.
تجدونه يحوي على خدع الثقافة الغربية
You're seeing the tuxedos, the bouquets.
ترون البذلات ، الباقات
But what's really, to me, frightening about the picture
لكن في الحقيقة ما أراه مروعاً في الصورة
and about this billboard is the refinery in the background.
و حول هذا اللوحة و الألات في الخلف
So it's like marrying up all the things that we have
كالتزاوج بين كل الاشياء التي نملكها
and it's an adaptation of our way of life, full stop.
وتعديل لاسلوبنا في الحياة.نقطة انتهى.
And again, when you start seeing that kind of embrace,
و مرة أخرى عندما تبدأ برؤية هذا النوع من الاحتضان
and you start looking at them leading their rural lifestyle
وتنظر اليهم على أنهم يعيشون حياتهم الريفية
with a very, very small footprint and moving into an urban lifestyle
تاركين ورائهم اثرا صغيرا جدا لينتقلوا الى الحياة المدنية
with a much higher footprint, it starts to become very sobering.
ذات الأثر الكبير ، فإن ذلك الواقع المؤلم.
This is a shot in one of the biggest squares in Guangdong --
هذه صورة لاحد اكبر الساحات في غواندونغ
and this is where a lot of migrant workers are coming in from the country.
وهذا المكان يتجمع فيه العمال المهاجرون من الريف
And there's about 130 million people in migration
وهناك ما يعادل 130 مليون مهاجر
trying to get into urban centers at all times,
يحاولون الوصول الى مراكز المدن دوما
and in the next 10 to 15 years, are expecting
وفي غضون العشر او الخمسة عشر سنة سنتوقع
another 400 to 500 million people to migrate
هجرة ما يقارب 400-500 مليون شخص
into the urban centers like Shanghai and the manufacturing centers.
الى مراكز المدن كشنغهاي و المراكز الصناعية
The manufacturers are --
المصنعين ---
the domestics are usually -- you can tell a domestic factory by the fact
المحلية هي عادة -- يمكنكم القول ان المصنع محلي من الواقع
that they all use the same color uniforms.
أنهم يستخدمون نفس الالوان في زيهم
So this is a pink uniform at this factory. It's a shoe factory.
هذا زي زهري في هذا المصنع، انه مصنع احذية
And they have dorms for the workers.
وفيه مساكن للعمال
So they bring them in from the country and put them up in the dorms.
اي يجلبونهم من الارياف ويسكنوهم هنا
This is one of the biggest shoe factories, the Yuyuan shoe factory
هذا احد اكبر مصانع الاحذية و اسمه يوييوان
near Shenzhen. It has 90,000 employees making shoes.
بالقرب من شينزين وفيه 90 الف عامل يصنع الاحذية
This is a shift change, one of three.
هنا تغيير ورديات العمال ، واحد من ثلاثة. في كل تغيير---
There's two factories of this scale in the same town.
هناك مصنعين من هذا الحجم في نفس البلدة
This is one with 45,000, so every lunch,
هذا المصنع فيه 45 الف عامل. اي في كل فترة غداء
there's about 12,000 coming through for lunch.
سيحضر ما يقارب 12 الف عامل
They sit down; they have about 20 minutes.
يجلسون و يتناولون الطعام لمدة 20 دقيقة
The next round comes in. It's an incredible workforce
وبعدها تاتي المناوبة التالية. انه قوة بشرية عاملة جبارة
that's building there. Shanghai --
ذلك العمران هناك. شنغهاي---
I'm looking at the urban renewal in Shanghai,
انا انظر الى التجديد المدني في شنغهاي
and this is a whole area that will be flattened
سوف تزال كل هذه المنطقة
and turned into skyscrapers in the next five years.
وتحول الى منطقة ناطحات سحاب في السنوات الخمس القادمة
What's also happening in Shanghai is --
وما يحدث في شنغهاي أيضاً هو
China is changing because this wouldn't have happened
ان الصين تتغير لانه ما كان لهذا ان يحدث
five years ago, for instance. This is a holdout.
قبل خمس سنوات مثلاً.
They're called dengzahoos -- they're like pin tacks to the ground.
يدعون "دنغزاهوس" -- مثل المسامير متشبثين بالأرض.
They won't move. They're not negotiating.
لن يتحركوا ولن يفاوضوا
They're not getting enough, so they're not going to move.
لم يحصلوا على مبلغ كاف، لذا لن يتزحزحوا من اماكنهم
And so they're holding off until they get a deal with them.
ولذلك سيبقون حتى يحصلون على اتفاق معهم
And they've been actually quite successful in getting better deals
وفي الحقيقة نجحوا في السابق بالحصول على اتفاقات افضل
because most of them are getting a raw deal.
لان معظمهم حصل على اتفاق اولي
They're being put out about two hours --
لقد اخرجوا لمدة ساعتين
the communities that have been around for literally hundreds of years,
المجتمعات التي كانت هنا لمئات السنين
or maybe even thousands of years,
او الاف السنين
are being broken up and spread across in the suburban areas
تفكك و تنشر في الضواحي
outside of Shanghai. But these are a whole series of guys
خارج شنغهاي. ولكن هؤلاء مجموعة من الشبان الجديين
holding out in this reconstruction of Shanghai.
يتمسكون ببناء شنغهاي
Probably the largest urban-renewal project, I think,
اعتقد انه اعظم مشروع تجديد مدني
ever attempted on the planet.
على وجه المعمورة
And then the embrace of the things that they're replacing it with --
ومن ثم الاشياء التي يستبدلونه بها
again, one of my wishes, and I never ended up going there,
من جديد، احد امنياتي و لم اذهب مطلقا الى هناك
was to somehow tell them that there were better ways to build a house.
ان اخبرهم عن طرق افضل لبناء البيوت
The kinds of collisions of styles and things were quite something,
فنوع انماط الابنية كانت شيئا عجيبا
and these are called the villas.
وهذه هي الفلل
And also, like right now, they're just moving.
و ايضا تنتقل
The scaffolding is still on, and this is an e-waste area,
ما تزال السقالات مبنية، وهذه مكب للنفايات الكهربائية
and if you looked in the foreground on the big print,
واذا نظرت الى الارض الامامية
you'd see that the industry -- their industry -- they're all recycling.
سترى ان صناعتهم كلها صناعة تدويرية
So the industry's already growing
اذا الصناعة تزدهر كثيراً
around these new developments.
وبجانب هذه التطورات الجديدة
This is a five-level bridge in Shanghai.
يوجد جسر من خمس طبقات في شنغهاي
Shanghai was a very intriguing city -- it's exploding on a level
كانت شانغهاي مدينة الفضول -- إنها تنفجر على مستوى
that I don't think any city has experienced.
ولا اعتقد انه يوجد مدينة جربت هذا التوسع
In fact, even Shenzhen, the economic zone --
حتى مدينة شينزين، الصناعية او المنطقة الصناعية
one of the first ones -- 15 years ago was about 100,000 people,
احد بواكير المدن-- قبل 15 سنة كان فيها 100 الف نسمة
and today it boasts about 10 to 11 million.
واليوم فيها ما يقارب 10-11 مليون نسمة
So that gives you an idea of the kinds of migrations and the speed with which --
لذلك هذا يعطيكم فكرة عن انواع الهجرات وسرعتها
this is just the taxis being built by Volkswagen.
هذه سيارات الأجرة يتم تصنيعها من قبل فوكس فاغن.
There's 9,000 of them here,
يوجد 9 الاف منها هنا
and they're being built for most of the big cities,
وتبنى من أجل معظم المدن الكبرى
Beijing and Shanghai, Shenzhen.
مثل بكين وشنغهاي و شنزين
And this isn't even the domestic car market; this is the taxi market.
وليس هذا سوق السيارات المحلي، هذا سوق سيارات الاجرة
And what we would see here as a suburban development --
وما نرى هنا هو نوع من التطوير المدني
a similar thing, but they're all high-rises.
شيء مشابه ، كلها تصعد نحو الأعلى.
So they'll put 20 or 40 up at a time,
لذا سيضعون من 20 او 40 في كل مرة
and they just go up in the same way
وسترتفع كلها بنفس الطريقة
as a single-family dwelling would go up here in an area.
مثل عائلة واحدة سترتفع في بنيانها
And the density is quite incredible.
والكثافة السكانية غير معقولة
And one of the things in this picture that I wanted to point out
واحد الاشياء في هذه الصورة التي اود الاشارة اليها
is that when I saw these kinds of buildings,
هو انني عندما رأيت هذه الانواع من الابنية
I was shocked to see
اصبت بالذهول لرؤية
that they're not using a central air-conditioning system;
انهم لا يستخدمون نظام تكييف مركزي
every window has an air conditioner in it.
كل نافذة كان فيها مكيف
And I'm sure there are people here who probably
وانا متأكد انه يوجد أشخاص هنا
know better than I do about efficiencies,
يعرفون بشكل افضل مني عن الكفاءة
but I can't imagine that every apartment having its own air conditioner
ولكني لا اتخيل ان لكل شقة مكيفها الخاص
is a very efficient way to cool a building on this scale.
ستكون طريقة فعالة لتبريد مبنى بهذا الكبر
And when you start looking at that,
وعندما تبدا النظر الى هذا
and then you start factoring up into a city the size of Shanghai,
و تبدأ بالحساب على مستوى مدينة كاملة بحجم شانغهاي
it's literally a forest of skyscrapers.
انها غابة من ناطحات السحاب
It's breathtaking, in terms of the speed at which this city is transforming.
شيء مذهل ، بالنظر إلى السرعة التي تتحول فيها هذه المدن
And you can see in the foreground of this picture,
ويمكنكم أن تروا في مقدمة هذه الصورة
it's still one of the last areas that was being held up.
انه اخر منطقة صامدة
Right now that's all cleared out -- this was done about eight months ago --
اما الان فكل شيء ذهب -- حدث هذا قبل ثمانية أشهر تقريباً
and high-rises are now going up into that central spot.
وارتفاعات شاهقة تظهر في تلك المنطقة المركزية
So a skyscraper is built, literally, overnight in Shanghai.
اي ان ناطحة السحاب تبنى بين ليلة وضحاها حرفيا في شانغهاي
Most recently I went in, and I started looking
مؤخرا ذهبت لهناك وبدأت بالنظر
at some of the biggest industries in China.
الى اكبر صناعات الصين
And this is Baosteel, right outside of Shanghai.
وهذه هي بوستيل خارج شنغهاي
This is the coal supply for the steel factory -- 18 square kilometers.
وهذا مصدر الفحم لمصنع الفولاذ-- مساحته 18 كيلو متر مربع
It's an incredibly massive operation, I think 15,000 workers,
عملية كبيرة جدا. اعتقد انه يوجد 15 الف عامل
five cupolas, and the sixth one's coming in here.
خمس من هذه الأجهزة و أعتقد أن السادسة على الطريق
So they're building very large blast furnaces
إنهم يبنون محطات صهر ضخمة جداً
to try to deal with the demand for steel in China.
في محاولة لمواجهة الطلب الكبير على الفولاذ في الصين
So this is three of the visible blast furnaces within that shot.
هذه ثلاث من هذه الأفران التي تظهر في لقطة واحدة
And again, looking at these images, there's this constant, like, haze that you're seeing.
ومن جديد عند النظر لهذه الصور يوجد هناك شيء مستمر غير واضح ترونه
This is going to show you, real time, an assembler. It's a circuit breaker.
هذه تبين لكم ، بالسرعة الفعلية ، عامل يقوم بتركيب فاصل جهد (فيوز)
10 hours a day at this speed.
10 ساعات في اليوم وبهذه السرعة
I think one of the issues
اعتقد احد القضايا
that we here are facing with China,
التي نواجهها مع الصين
is that they're using a lot of the latest production technology.
انهم يستخدمون الكثير من التكنولوجيا الحديثة
In that one, there were 400 people that worked on the floor.
في تلك الصورة يوجد تقريباً 400 شخص يعملون على الارض
And I asked the manager to point out five of your fastest producers,
وسالت المدير ان يشير الى خمسة من اسرع المنتجين
and then I went and looked at each one of them for about 15 or 20 minutes,
وذهبت بعدها ونظرت الى كل واحد لمدة 15 او 20 دقيقة
and picked this one woman.
واخترت هذه المرأة
And it was just lightning fast;
وكانت كسرعة البرق
the way she was working was almost unbelievable.
الطريقة التي تعمل بها لا تصدق
But that is the trick that they've got right now,
وهذه هي الحيلة التي اتقنوها هنا
that they're winning with, is that they're using
والتي يفوزون من خلالها وهي انهم يستخدمون
all the latest technologies and extrusion machines,
جميع التقنيات الحديثة و أجهزة الحقن
and bringing all the components into play,
ووضع كل المكونات في التشغيل
but the assembly is where they're actually bringing in --
لكن التجميع هو الذي يحضرون فيه
the country workers are very willing to work. They want to work.
العمال الريفيين يريدون العمل بشغف
There's a massive backlog of people wanting their jobs.
هناك حشد كبير من الاشخاص يريد العمل
That condition's going to be there for the next 10 to 15 years
ذلك الوضع سيبقى لمدة 10-15 سنة
if they realize what they want, which is, you know,
وإذا ادركوا ما يريدون و هو كما تعلمون
400 to 500 million more people coming into the cities.
400-500 مليون شخص ياتي للمدن
In this particular case -- this is the assembly line that you saw;
في هذه الحالة بالذات -- وهذا هو خط التجميع الذي رأيته ،
this is a shot of it.
وهذه لقطة من ذلك.
I had to use a very small aperture to get the depth of field.
اضطررت لاستخدام فتحة صغيرة جدا للحصول على عمق الميدان.
I had to have them freeze for 10 seconds to get this shot.
كان علي أن أطلب منهم التجمد لمدة 10 ثوان للحصول على هذه اللقطة.
It took me five fake tries
استغرق الأمر مني خمس محاولات وهمية
because they were just going. To slow them down was literally impossible.
لأنهم كانوا في حركة دائمة و كان إبطاؤهم مستحيل حرفيا.
They were just wound up doing these things all day long,
كانوا مشغولين بالقيام بهذا العمل طوال النهار
until the manager had to, with a stern voice, say,
حتى طلب منهم المدير و بصوت صارم
"Okay, everybody freeze."
"حسناً ، فليتوقف الجميع "
It wasn't too bad,
لم تكن سيئة للغاية ،
but they're driven to produce these things at an incredible rate.
ولكنهم مندفعين إلى إنتاج هذه الأشياء بمعدل لا يصدق.
This is a textile mill doing synthetic silk, an oil byproduct.
هذا معمل نسيج يصنع حرير صناعي ، وهو ناتج ثانوي للنفط.
And what you're seeing here is,
وما ترونه هنا هو ،
again, one of the most state-of-the-art textile mills.
مرة أخرى ، أحد أهم مصانع النسيج عالية التقنية.
There are 500 of these machines; they're worth about 200,000 dollars each.
هناك 500 من هذه الآلات ، و تبلغ قيمتها نحو 200000 دولار لكل منهما.
So you have about 12 people running this,
بحيث يكون لديك نحو 12 شخصا لتشغيل هذا ،
and they're just inspecting it -- and they're just walking the lines.
يقومون فقط بتفحصها -- يقومون فقط بالمشي بين تلك الآلات
The machines are all running,
جميع الآلات تعمل
absolutely incredible to see what the scale of industries are.
من المذهل رؤية حجم هذه الصناعات
And I started getting in further and further into the factories.
وبدأت في العثور على مزيد ومزيد من المصانع.
And that's a diptych. I do a lot of pairings
وهذا هو اللوح المزدوج ، ولذا فإنني أقوم بعمل أزواج
to try and get the sense of scale in these places.
لمحاولة الشعور بالحجم في هذه الأماكن.
This is a line where they get the threads
هذا هو الخط الذي يحصلون فيه على الخيوط
and they wind the threads together,
و يقومون بجدل الخيوط مع بعضها
pre-going into the textile mills.
لتجهيزها قبل الدخول إلى المصنع
Here's something that's far more labor-intensive,
هنا شيء يتطلب جهداً بشرياً أكثر
which is the making of shoes.
والذي هو صناعة الأحذية.
This floor has about 1,500 workers on this floor.
يوجد نحو 1500 عامل في هذا الطابق.
The company itself had about 10,000 employees,
الشركة نفسها لديها حوالي 10000 موظف ،
and they're doing domestic shoes.
ويصنعون أحذية للسكان المحليين.
It was very hard to get into the international companies
كان من الصعب جدا للوصول الى الشركات الدولية
because I had to get permission from companies like Nike and Adidas,
لأنه كان علي الحصول على تصريح من شركات مثل نايكي وأديداس ،
and that's very hard to get.
وأنه من الصعب جدا الحصول عليها.
And they don't want to let me in.
وانهم لا يريدون السماح لي بالدخول و
But the domestic was much easier to do.
لكن المحلي كان أسهل بكثير.
It just gives you a sense of, again -- and that's where,
فإنه يوفر لك الشعور ، ومرة أخرى -- وهذا هو المكان ،
really, the whole migration of jobs started going over to China
حقا ، هجرة كاملة للوظائف بدأت بالانتقال للصين
and making the shoes. Nike was one of the early ones.
وصنع الأحذية. نايكي كانت من الأوائل.
It was such a high labor component to it
وكان حقا -- يوجد عامل يتعلق بالعمالة بشكل كبير
that it made a lot of sense to go after that labor market.
و كان من المنطقي بعد ذلك الذهاب إلى سوق العمالة
This is a high-tech mobile phone: Bird mobile phone,
هذا أحد الهواتف المحمولة العالية التقنية
one of the largest mobile makers in China.
واحدة من أكبر صانعي الهاتف النقال في الصين.
I think mobile phone companies
وأعتقد أن شركات الهاتف النقال
are popping up, literally, on a weekly basis,
التي تظهر ، حرفيا ، على أساس أسبوعي ،
and they have an explosive growth in mobile phones.
وكان لديهم نمو هائل في الهواتف المحمولة.
This is a textile where they're doing shirts --
هذا هو الغزل والنسيج حيث يصنعون القمصان.
Youngor, the biggest shirt factory and clothing factory in China.
يونجور ، اكبر مصنع للقمصان و الملابس فى الصين.
And this next shot here is one of the lunchrooms.
وهذه اللقطة التالية هنا هي واحدة من غرف الطعام.
Everything is very efficient.
كل شيء فعال جدا.
While setting up this shot,
أثناء إعداد هذه اللقطة،
people on average would spend eight to 10 minutes having a lunch.
كان الناس يقضون في المتوسط 8 حتي 10 دقيقة لتناول وجبة غداء.
This was one of the biggest factories I've ever seen.
كانت هذه واحدة من أكبر المصانع التي شاهدتها على الاطلاق.
They make coffeemakers here, the biggest coffeemaker
هنا يصنعون أجهزة تحضير القهوة ، أكبر صانع للقهوة
and the biggest iron makers --
و أكبر مصنع للحديد
they make 20 million of them in the world.
يصنعون منها 20 مليونا في العالم.
There's 21,000 employees. This one factory -- and they had several of them --
هناك 21000 موظف. في هذا المصنع الواحد -- وكان لديهم العديد منهم --
is half a kilometer long.
طوله نصف كيلومتر.
These are just recently shot -- I just came back about a month ago,
هذه من الصور الحديثة -- لقد عدت للتو قبل نحو شهر ،
so you're the first ones to be seeing these,
لذلك أنتم أول من يتمكن من رؤية هذه ،
these new factory pictures I've taken.
صور المصانع الجديدة التي التقطتها.
So it's taken me almost a year to gain access into these places.
تتطلب الأمر حوالي السنة للتمكن من الدخول الى هذه الأماكن.
The other aspect of what's happening in China
في جانب آخر من جوانب ما يحدث في الصين
is that there's a real need for materials there.
هو أن هناك حاجة حقيقية للمواد هناك.
So a lot of the recycled materials that are collected here
حتى الكثير من المواد المعاد تدويرها التي تم جمعها هنا
are being recycled and taken to China by ships.
يتم إعادة تدويرها و إرسالها إلى الصين في السفن.
That's cubed metal. This is armatures, electrical armatures,
هذا المعدن المكعب. هذه هي المحركات ، المحركات الكهربائية
where they're getting the copper and the high-end steel
حيث يحصلون على النحاس والصلب الراقي
from electrical motors out, and recycling them.
من المحركات الكهربائية ، وإعادة تدويرها.
This is certainly connected to California and Silicon Valley.
يرتبط هذا بالتأكيد مع وادي السيليكون في كاليفورنيا.
But this is what happens to most of the computers.
ولكن هذا هو ما يحدث لمعظم أجهزة الكمبيوتر.
Fifty percent of the world's computers end up in China to be recycled.
50 في المئة من أجهزة الكمبيوتر في العالم تنتهي في الصين لإعادة تدويرها.
It's referred to as "e-waste" there.
ويشار إلىيها على أنها النفايات الإلكترونية.
And it is a bit of a problem. The way they recycle the boards
و جزء من المشكلة.الطريقة التي يقومون بها بإعادة تدوير الألواح
is that they actually use the coal briquettes,
هي أنهم يستخدمون قوالب الفحم ،
which are used all through China, but they heat up the boards,
والتي تستخدم في جميع أنحاء الصين ، لكنهم يقومون بتسخين الألواح ،
and with pairs of pliers they pull off all the components.
وباستخدام أزواج من الكماشات يقومون بنزع كافة المكونات.
They're trying to get all the valued metals out of those components.
انهم يحاولون الحصول على جميع المعادن القيمة من تلك المكونات.
But the toxic smells -- when you come into a town
ولكن الروائح السامة -- عندما تأتي الى مدينة
that's actually doing this kind of burning of the boards,
فيها هذا النوع من العمل ،
you can smell it a good five or 10 kilometers before you get there.
يمكنك أن تشم الرائحة جيداً قبل خمس أو 10 كيلومترات قبل الوصول إلى هناك.
Here's another operation. It's all cottage industries,
إليكم عملية أخرى ، مناطق صناعية ريفية
so it's not big places -- it's all in people's front porches,
حتى انها ليست أماكن كبيرة -- انها كل ما في الشرفات الأمامية الشعبية
in their backyards, even in their homes they're burning boards,
، في ديارهم ، وحتى في منازلهم يقومون بحرق الألواح.
if there's a concern for somebody coming by --
إذا كان هناك قلق بالنسبة لشخص يمر من هنالك
because it is considered in China to be illegal, doing it,
لأنها تعتبر في الصين غير مشروعة ،
but they can't stop the product from coming in.
لكنهم لا يستطيعون وقف المنتج من القدوم.
This portrait -- I'm not usually known for portraits,
هذه الصورة الشخصية ، و أنا لا أعرَف عادة بهذه الصور ،
but I couldn't resist this one, where she's been through Mao,
ولكني لم أتمكن من مقاومتها، حيث انها كانت من خلال ماو
and she's been through the Great Leap Forward,
وانها كانت من خلال القفزة الكبرى الى الامام
and the Cultural Revolution, and now she's sitting on her porch
والثورة الثقافية ، وانها الآن تجلس على الشرفة
with this e-waste beside her. It's quite something.
مع هذه النفايات الإلكترونية بجانبها.شيء مذهل فعلاً.
This is a road where it's been shored up by computer boards
هذا هو الطريق الذي عبد من قبل لوحات الكمبيوتر
in one of the biggest towns where they're recycling.
في واحدة من أكبر المدن حيث يقومون بإعادة التدوير.
So that's the photographs that I wanted to show you.
هذه هي الصور التي أردت أن أريها لكما.
(Applause)
تصفيق
I want to dedicate my wishes to my two girls.
اريد ان اهدي تمنياتي لابنتي.
They've been sitting on my shoulder the whole time while I've been thinking.
لقد كانوا يجلسون على كتفي طوال الوقت بينما كنت أفكر.
One's Megan, the one of the right, and Katja there.
احدها ميغان ، التي على اليمين ، وكاتيا هناك.
And to me the whole notion --
وبالنسبة لي الفكرة الكاملة --
the things I'm photographing are out of a great concern
الأشياء التي أصورها هي مصدر قلق كبير
about the scale of our progress and what we call progress.
بشأن حجم التقدم الذي أحرزناه وما نسميه التقدم.
And as much as there are great things around the corner --
وبقدر ما هناك اشياء عظيمة قاب قوسين أو أدنى --
and it's palpable in this room --
وهو واضح في هذه القاعة --
of all of the things that are just about to break
من جميع الأشياء التي هي على وشك الظهور
that can solve so many problems,
يمكن أن تحل الكثير من المشاكل ،
I'm really hoping that those things will spread around the world
وأنا آمل حقا أن هذه الأمور سوف تنتشر في جميع أنحاء العالم.
and will start to have a positive effect.
و تبدأ بالتأثير إيجابياً.
And it isn't something that isn't just affecting our world,
وهذه أشياء لا تؤثر فقط في عالمنا ،
but it starts to go up -- because I think we can start correcting
لأنها تبدأ بالانتشار و الصعود --- و أنا أؤمن بأننا يمكن أن نبدأ بتصحيح
our footprint and bring it down -- but there's a growing footprint
آثار استهلاكنا -- و لكن الاستهلاك يتزايد بشكل كبير
that's happening in Asia, and is growing at a rapid, rapid rate,
هذا يحدث في آسيا ، و ينمو بمعدل سريع وسريع جداً ،
and so I don't think we can equalize it. So ultimately the strategy,
ولذا فإنني لا أعتقد أنه يمكننا تحقيق المساواة. و لكن في النهاية يجب أن تكون الاستراتيجية
I think, here is that we have to be very concerned about their evolution,
أعتقد ، وهنا يتعين علينا أن تكون قلقا للغاية حول تطورهم.
because it is going to be connected to our evolution as well.
لأنها سوف تكون متصلة بتطورنا كذلك.
So part of my thinking, and part of my wishes,
ذلك جزء من تفكيري ، وجزء من أمنياتي ،
is sitting with these thoughts in mind,
وهو الجلوس مع هذه الأفكار في عقلنا ،
and thinking about,
والتفكير ،
"How is their life going to be when they want to have children,
"كيف ستكون حياتهم عندما يريدون إنجاب الأطفال ،
or when they're ready to get married 20 years from now -- or whatever,
أو عندما يكونون على استعداد للزواج 20 سنة من الآن؟ -- أو أيا كان ،
15 years from now?"
15 عاما من الآن ؟"
And to me that has been the core behind most of my thinking --
وبالنسبة لي كان هذا جوهر ما كان وراء معظم تفكيري.
in my work, and also for this incredible chance to have some wishes.
في عملي ، وأيضا لهذا الفرصة التي لا تصدق لدينا بعض التمنيات.
Wish one: world-changing. I want to use my images
الأمنية الأولى : تغيير العالم .أريد استخدام صوري
to persuade millions of people to join in the global conversation on sustainability.
لاقناع الملايين من الناس على المشاركة في الحوار العالمي على الاستدامة.
And it is through communications today
ومن خلال الاتصالات اليوم
that I believe that that is not an unreal idea.
أعتقد أنها ليست فكرة غير واقعية.
Oh, and I went in search -- I wanted to put what I had in mind,
وتابعت البحث --- أردت أن أضع ما في فكري
hitch it onto something. I didn't want a wish just to start from nowhere.
ومركزاً على شيئ ما. لم ارغب ان ابدأ من لاشيء
One of them I'm starting from almost nothing, but the other one,
أحدها بدأتها من لا شيء تقريبا ، ولكن الأخرى ،
I wanted to find out what's going on that's working right now.
كنت أرغب في معرفة ما يحدث على هذا العمل الآن.
And Worldchanging.com is a fantastic blog, and that blog
و يوجد منتدى رائع Worldchanging.com
is now being visited by close to half-a-million people a month.
ويزوره ما يقرب من نصف مليون شخص في الشهر.
And it just started about 14 months ago.
وبدأت للتو منذ حوالى 14 شهرا .
And the beauty of what's going on there
وجمال ما يحدث هناك
is that the tone of the conversation is the tone that I like.
هو ان لهجة الحديث هو النغمة التي أحب.
What they're doing there is that they're not --
ما يفعلونه هناك هو انهم لا ---
I think the environmental movement has failed
أعتقد أن الحركة البيئية قد فشلت
in that it's used the stick too much;
في انها استخدمت العصا كثيرا.
it's used the apocalyptic tone too much;
استخدمت اللهجة المروعة كثيراً
it hasn't sold the positive aspects of
انها تقنع الجوانب الإيجابية
being environmentally concerned and trying to pull us out.
لما يجري بيئيا ومحاولة إخراجنا من هذه الورطة ،
Whereas this conversation that is going on in this blog
في حين أن هذا الحوار الذي يجري في هذا المنتدى
is about positive movements,
هو حول الحركات الإيجابية.
about how to change our world in a better way, quickly.
حول كيفية تغيير عالمنا بطريقة أفضل ، وبسرعة.
And it's looking at technology, and it's looking at new energy-saving devices,
وانها تبحث في التكنولوجيا ، وانها تبحث في الأجهزة الجديدة الموفرة للطاقة ،
and it's looking at how to rethink and how to re-strategize
وانها تبحث في كيفية التفكير وكيفية إعادة وضع استراتيجية
the movement towards sustainability.
التحرك نحو الاستدامة.
And so for me, one of the things that I thought
وهكذا بالنسبة لي ، فإن أحد الاشياء التي اعتقدت
would be to put some of my work in the service of promoting
أن أضع جزء من عملي في خدمة تعزيز
the Worldchanging.com website.
موقع Worldchanging.com.
Some of you might know, he's a TEDster -- Stephen Sagmeister and I
البعض منكم قد يعرف ، انه من أعضاء TED ستيفن ساغمايستر وأنا
are working on some layouts. And this is still in preliminary stages;
نعمل على بعض التخطيطات. وهذا لا يزال في المراحل الأولية.
these aren't the finals. But these images, with Worldchanging.com,
هذه ليست كل شيء .ولكن مع هذه الصور ، مع Worldchanging.com
can be placed into any kind of media.
يمكن وضعها في أي نوع من وسائل الاعلام.
They could be posted through the Web;
ويمكن نشرها من خلال شبكة الإنترنت ،
they could be used as a billboard or a bus shelter, or anything of that nature.
يمكن أن تستخدم على أنها لوحة أو على مراب للحافلات ، أو أي شيء من هذا القبيل.
So we're looking at this as trying to build out.
لذلك نحن نبحث في هذا الأمر في محاولة نشر هذه الفكرة
And what we ended up discussing
و انتهى بنا الأمر بمناقشة
was that in most media you get mostly an image with a lot of text,
أنه في معظم وسائل الاعلام تحصل في الغالب على صورة مع الكثير من النص ،
and the text is blasted all over.
والنص منتشر في كل مكان.
What was unusual, according to Stephen,
ما كان غير عادي ، وفقا لستيفن ،
is less than five percent of ads are actually leading with image.
هو أنه أقل من خمسة في المئة من الإعلانات التي تقود في الواقع مع الصورة.
And so in this case,
وبالتالي في هذه الحالة ،
because it's about a lot of these images and what they represent,
لأنه يدور حول الكثير من هذه الصور وما تمثله ،
and the kinds of questions they bring up,
وأنواع الأسئلة التي تطرحها ،
that we thought letting the images play out and bring someone to say,
كنا نظن أن ترك الصور تلعب وتقديم شخص ما ليقول :
"Well, what's Worldchanging.com, with these images, have to do?"
"حسنا ، ما علاقة Worldchanging.com ، مع هذه الصور؟ "
And hopefully inspire people to go to that website.
ونأمل أن ذلك سيلهم الناس على الذهاب إلى ذلك الموقع.
So Worldchanging.com, and building that blog, and it is a blog,
إذاً Worldchanging.com ، وبناء ذلك المنتدى،
and I'm hoping that it isn't -- I don't see it as the kind of blog
وأنا على أمل أنها ليست -- وأنا لا أرى أنها نوع من المنتديات
where we're all going to follow each other to death.
حيث نقوم بمتابعة بعضنا البعض حتى الموت.
This one is one that will spoke out, and will go out,
هذه أحدها سوف تظهر ، وسوف تخرج ،
and to start reaching. Because right now there's conversations
وستبدأ بالتأثير. لأنه يوجد الآن الكثير من الحوارات الآن،
in India, in China, in South America --
في الهند ، في الصين ، في أمريكا الجنوبية --
there's entries coming from all around the world.
هناك طروحات قادمة من جميع أنحاء العالم.
I think there's a chance to have a dialogue, a conversation
أعتقد أن هناك فرصة لإجراء حوار ، محادثة
about sustainability at Worldchanging.com.
حول الاستدامة في Worldchanging.com.
And anything that you can do to promote that would be fantastic.
وأي شيء يمكنك القيام به لتعزيز هذا سيكون رائعا.
Wish two is more of the bottom-up, ground-up one that I'm trying to work with.
الأمنية الثانية :وهي أكثر من أسفل إلى أعلى ، من القاعدة الى القمة أحاول العمل عليها.
And this one is: I wish to launch a groundbreaking competition
وهي : أود أن أطلق مسابقة رائدة
that motivates kids to invest ideas on, and invent ideas on, sustainability.
تدفع الأطفال للاستثمار في الأفكار ، وابتكار الأفكار المتعلقة بالاستدامة.
And one of the things that came out --
و أحد الأشياء التي خرجت بعد تفكير ----
Allison, who actually nominated me, said something earlier on
وقالت أليسون ، التي رشحتني في الواقع ، في وقت سابق
in a brainstorming. She said that recycling in Canada
في جلسات العصف الذهني وقالت إن إعادة التدوير في كندا
had a fantastic entry into our psyche through kids between grade four and six.
كان لدخوله أثر رائع في نفسيتنا من خلال أطفال تتراوح أعمارهم بين الصف الرابع و السادس.
And you think about it, you know,
وأنت تفكر في ذلك ، كما تعلمون ،
grade four -- my wife and I, we say age seven is the age of reason,
الصف الرابع -- أنا وزوجتي ، نقول سن السابعة من العمر هو عمر التحليل ،
so they're into the age of reason. And they're pre-puberty.
وانهم ما قبل سن البلوغ.
So it's this great window where they actually are --
لذلك فمن هذه النافذة الكبيرة حيث هم في الواقع --
you can influence them. You know what happens at puberty?
يمكنك التأثير عليهم. أنت تعرف ماذا يحدث في سن البلوغ؟
You know, we know that from earlier presentations.
تعلمون ، ونحن نعلم من العروض في وقت سابق.
So my thinking here is that we try to motivate those kids
إذن ، تفكيري هنا هو أن نحاول تحفيز هؤلاء الأطفال
to start driving home ideas. Let them understand what sustainability is,
للبدء بتطوير أفكارهم الخاصة . دعوهم يفهمون ما هي الاستدامة ،
and that they have a vested interest in it to happen.
وبأن لديهم مصلحة في أن يحدث ذلك.
And one of the ways I thought of doing it is to use my prize,
واحدة من الطرق التي فكرت في القيام بها هي استخدام جائزتي
so I would take 30,000 or 40,000 dollars of the winnings,
لذلك أود أن آخذ 30000 أو 40000 دولار من الأرباح ،
and the rest is going to be to manage this project,
والباقي سيكون لإدارة هذا المشروع.
but to use that as prizes for kids to get into their hands.
ولكن لاستخدام ذلك كجوائز للأطفال تصل الى ايديهم.
But the other thing that I thought would be fantastic
ولكن الشيء الآخر الذي اعتقدت أنه سيكون رائعا
was to create these -- call them "prize targets."
لإنشاء هذه -- ندعوها أهداف للجوائز.
And so one could be for the best sustainable idea
وهكذا يمكن لأحدها أن تكون لفكرة عن أفضل
for an in-school project, the best one for a household project,
مشروع استدامة في المدرسة. و أخرى لأفضل مشروع منزلي.
or it could be the best community project for sustainability.
أو يمكن أن تكون لأفضل مشروع مجتمعي لتحقيق الاستدامة.
And I also thought there should be a nice prize
واعتقدت أيضا أنه يجب أن يكون هناك جائزة لطيفة
for the best artwork for "In My World." And what would happen --
للحصول على أفضل الأعمال الفنية لـ "في عالمي" والذي سيحدث --
it's a scalable thing. And if we can get people to put in things --
انه شيء قابل للتحجيم. وإذا تمكنا من حث الناس لوضع الامور في --
whether it's equipment, like a media lab,
سواء معدات انها ، مثل مختبر وسائط الإعلام ،
or money to make the prize significant enough --
أو المال لجعل الجائزة كبيرة بما فيه الكفاية --
and to open it up to all the schools that are public schools,
وفتح المجال ليصل إلى جميع المدارس التي هي مدارس عامة
or schools that are with kids that age,
أو المدارس التي هي مع أطفال هذا السن ،
and make it a wide-open competition for them
وجعلها منافسة واسعة مفتوحة لهم
to go after those prizes and to submit them.
للذهاب وراء تلك الجوائز وتقديمها إليهم.
And the prize has to be a verifiable thing, so it's not about just ideas.
والجائزة يجب أن تكون شيء يمكن التحقق منه ، حتى انها ليست مجرد أفكار.
The art pieces are about the ideas and how they present them
القطع الفنية هي حول الأفكار وكيف يتم تقديمها
and do them, but the actual things have to be verifiable.
والقيام بها ، ولكن الأمور الفعلية يجب أن تكون قابلة للتحقق.
In that way, what's happening is that
وبهذه الطريقة ، ما يحدث هو
we're motivating a certain age group to start thinking.
أننا نقوم بتحفيز فئة عمرية معينة للبدء في التفكير.
And they're going to push that up, from the bottom -- up into,
وسوف ينطلقون من هنالك
I believe, into the households. And parents will be reacting to it,
وسوف يقوم الآباء بالرد عليها ،
and trying to help them with the projects.
ومحاولة مساعدتهم في المشاريع.
And I think it starts to motivate the whole idea towards sustainability
وأعتقد أنه سيبدأ بتحفيز الفكرة كلها نحو الاستدامة
in a very positive way,
بطريقة إيجابية جدا ،
and starts to teach them. They know about recycling now,
ويبدأ في تعليمهم. وهم يعرفون الآن الكثير عن إعادة التدوير
but they don't really, I think, get sustainability in all the things,
لكنهم حقا ، وأعتقد ، لا يفهمون الاستدامة في جميع الأشياء ،
and the energy footprint, and how that matters.
والأثر الاستهلاكي والطاقة ، وكيف أن الأمور تؤثر.
And to teach them, to me, would be a fantastic wish,
وتعليمهم ، بالنسبة لي ، سيكون أمنية رائعة ،
and it would be something that I would certainly put my shoulder into.
وسيكون شيئا سأقوم بالتأكيد بدفعه للأمام
And again, in "In My World," the competition --
ومرة أخرى ، في "عالمي" ، والمنافسة --
we would use the artwork that comes in from that competition to promote it.
نود أن استخدام العمل الفني الذي يأتي من أن المنافسة في الترويج له.
And I like the words, "in my world,"
وأنا أحب عبارة : "في عالمي ،"
because it gives possession of the world to the person who's doing it.
لأنه يعطي الشعور بامتلاك العالم من أجل الشخص الذي يقوم بذلك.
It is my world; it's not someone else's. I want to help it;
إنه عالمي ، و ليس لشخص آخر ، أريد أن أساعده.
I want to do something with it. So I think it has a great opportunity
أريد أن أفعل شيئا به. -- لذلك اعتقد انه لديه فرصة كبيرة
to engage the imaginations -- and great ideas, I think, come from kids --
لإشراك الخيال -- والأفكار العظيمة ، كما أعتقد ، تأتي من الاطفال
and engage their imagination into a project,
وإشراك خيالهم في مشروع ما
and do something for schools.
والقيام بشيء ما للمدارس.
I think all schools could use extra equipment, extra cash --
أعتقد أن جميع المدارس بحاجة إلى بعض التجهيزات الإضافية ، و بعض المال أيضاً
it's going to be an incentive for them to do that.
و سيكون ذلك محفزاً لهم للمشاركة بذلك
And these are some of the ideas in terms of where
وهذه هي بعض الأفكار من حيث
we could possibly put in some promotion for "In My World."
ما يمكننا القيام به لتعزيز "في عالمي."
And wish three is: Imax film. So I was told I should do one for myself,
وأمنيتي الثالثة فيلم آيماكس. قيل لي أنه يجب أن أقوم به لوحدي ،
and I've always wanted to actually get involved with doing something.
وكنت أريد دائما أن أتعامل مع الواقع والقيام بشيء.
And the scale of my work, and the kinds of ideas I'm playing with --
ونطاق عملي ، وأنواع الأفكار التي كنت ألعب معها --
when I first saw an Imax film, I almost immediately thought,
عندما رأيت أول فيلم آيماكس ، بدأت على الفور بالتفكير
"There's a real resonance between what I'm trying to do
"هناك صدى حقيقي بين ما أحاول القيام به ،
and the scale of what I try to do as a photographer."
وحجم ما أحاول القيام به كمصور. "
And I think there's a real possibility
وأعتقد أن هناك إمكانية حقيقية --
to reach new audiences if I had a chance.
للوصول إلى جمهور جديد إذا سنحت لي الفرصة.
So I'm looking, really, for a mentor, because I just had my birthday.
لذلك أنا أبحث ، حقا ، لمعلم ، لأنه كان عيد ميلادي منذ فترة.
I'm 50, and I don't have time to go back to school right now --
أنا ابن 50 ، وليس لدي الوقت للذهاب إلى المدرسة في الوقت الراهن --.
I'm too busy. So I need somebody
أنا مشغول جدا و لذلك فإنني بحاجة إلى شخص
who can put me on a quick catch-up course on how to do something like that,
يمكن أن يضعني في دورة سريعة لتعلم كيفية القيام بشيء ما من هذا القبيل ،
and lead me through the maze of how one does something like this.
وليقودني عبر متاهة كيفية قيام الناس بشيء من هذا القبيل.
That would be fantastic. So those are my three wishes.
وسيكون ذلك رائعا. و كانت تلك هي أمنياتي الثلاث .
(Applause)
تصفيق